We can travel the worlds!
The Green Dinosaur is a animation, family, adventure
film directed by Wojtek Wawszczyk.
When the world around him is mysteriously erased, a little green dinosaur named Diplodocus must travel
through the pages of a comic book and adventure through time to bring color back to his land.
Alongside a wizard and two scientists, Diplo’s plans go awry as he learns that
there may be a dimension to his world that he never considered.
Diplodok (voice), played by Mikołaj Wachowski.
Hokus Pokus / Hokus Pokus' Father (voice), played by Borys Szyc.
Entomologia (voice), played by Małgorzata Kożuchowska.
Professor Nerwosolek / Diplodok's Grandfather
(voice), played by Arkadiusz Jakubik.
Tadek, played by Piotr Polak.
Publisher, played by Helena Englert.
Dinosaur is a 2000 American live-action animated  adventure film directed by Ralph Zondag and
Eric Leighton and written by John Harrison, Robert Nelson Jacobs, and Walon Green.
Produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation and The
Secret Lab, it stars the voices of D.
Sweeney, Alfre Woodard, Ossie Davis, Max Casella, Hayden Panettiere, Samuel E.
Wright, Julianna Margulies, Peter Siragusa, Joan Plowright, and Della Reese.
The film follows a young Iguanodon who was adopted and raised
by a family of lemurs on a tropical island.
They are forced to the mainland by a catastrophic meteorite impact; setting out to find a new home, they join a herd of dinosaurs heading for
the "Nesting Grounds", but must contend with the group's harsh leader, as well as external dangers such as predatory Carnotaurus.
The initial idea was conceived in 1986 by Phil Tippett and Paul Verhoeven, which
they conceived as a darker, naturalistic film about dinosaurs.
The project underwent numerous iterations with multiple directors attached.
In 1994, Walt Disney Feature Animation began development on the project and spent
several years developing the software to create the dinosaurs.
While the characters in Dinosaur are computer-generated, most of the
backgrounds are live-action and were filmed on location.
A number of backgrounds were found in various continents such as the Americas
and Asia; various tepuis and Angel Falls also appear in the film.
With a budget of $127.5 million, Dinosaur was reportedly the
most expensive computer-animated film at the time.
Dinosaur is also the first film from Walt Disney
Feature Animation to be 3D animated.
Dinosaur was released on May 19, 2000, to mixed reviews from critics, who praised the film's opening
sequence, soundtrack and animation, but criticized the story, screenplay and lack of originality.
The film grossed $349.8 million worldwide, becoming the
fifth highest-grossing film of 2000.
It became the fourth best-selling home video release of 2001, selling
10.6 million copies and garnering $198 million in sales.
The film explores themes of comic book, breaking the
fourth wall, dinosaur, philosophical, playful.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.